<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Tour Guide App</string>
    <string name="restaurants">Lounges</string>
    <string name="places">Places</string>
    <string name="food">Food</string>
    <string name="events">Events</string>
    <string name="place_cantabria">Cantabria</string>
    <string name="event_cantabria">La Semana Grande de Santander</string>
    <string name="description_semana_grande">The 25th of July is Santiago\'s day. In his honor, the city of Santander celebrates the \"Big Week\" of celebrations, which starts in the city hall and then goes around the city. During the celebrations there are concerts, activities, scenic art shows, fireworks, gastronomic booths y popular contests. Also, during this week it takes places in Cuatro Caminos the bullfighting festival of Santiago, one of the most important ones in the north of Spain."</string>
    <string name="place_murcia">Comunidad de Murcia</string>
    <string name="salinas_pedro">Salinas de Pedro</string>
    <string name="description_salinas_pedro">The Regional Park of Las Salinas y Arenales de San Pedro del Pinatar is a wetland area which covers 856 hectares, and includes salt flats, dunes and beaches between the Mar Menor and the Mediterranean. It is one of the most important locations in San Pedro del Pinatar, not only for its value as a tourist attraction, but also for its value as an area of environmental importance and the wildlife it attracts, particularly the birdlife (including flamingos!) which draws enthousiasts from across the Region of Murcia. \n \nA special information centre is located close to the entrance to the park, containing a vast range of info about the park, its flora and fauna.</string>
    <string name="place_castilla_mancha">Castilla-La Mancha</string>
    <string name="almagro">Almagro</string>
    <string name="description_almagro">Almagro is a town and municipality situated in Ciudad Real province.Almagro lies within small Paleozoic mountain ranges, with some reserves of shallow creeks, including the Pellejero and de Cuetos. It also lies within a volcanic zone (Cerrro de la Yezosa), which lies upon a quartzite massif. It makes the zone particularly unique, together with that of the zones of Olot and Cabo de Gata, in the sense that it is one of the few important zones of volcanic origin in the Iberian Peninsula. \n \nAn International Festival of Classical Theater has also been celebrated here annually since 1978.Cereal, vines, olives, and cotton are grown and cultivated here; there are also livestock and herding. There are also quarries of basalt and mines of manganese and plaster. A traditional industry is the fashioning of appliqué lace and pillow lace (encaje de bolillos). Other industries include woodworking and construction.</string>
    <string name="cabarceno">Parque de la Naturaleza de Cabárceno</string>
    <string name="description_cabarceno">The cabarceno natural park is not a zoo conventional or a natural park . It is a naturalized space by the hand of man, from the primitive beauty of the karst landscape on the 750 ha of a former open pit mining. In the Nature Park Cabárceno life it develops in the most natural environment for the animals that inhabit it. Except food provided to them, the rest of the activities are marked by their almost total freedom and instinct. Virtually all fights and struggles trigger mating season for control of females and of course, except the survival instinct, the rest of your senses are so wild and in its natural habitat. \n \nToday for its enormous quality facilities cabarceno natural park they are among the best rated by the agencies that monitor the living conditions of animals. The Cabárceno Natural Park is designed with educational, cultural, scientific and recreational purposes, having become one of the greatest tourist attractions of northern Spain.</string>
    <string name="place_cataluña">Cataluña</string>
    <string name="riglos">Mallos de Riglos</string>
    <string name="description_riglos">Mallets of Riglos are a set of conglomerate rock formations, located in the municipality of Las Peñas de Riglos, in the Hoya de Huesca comarca, in Aragon, Spain. They are located near Las Peñas de Riglos some 45 km (28 mi) to the northwest of the city of Huesca. Rising to some 300 metres (980 ft) high (c. 1000 metres or 3,300 ft (1,000 m) above sea level), they form part of the foothills of the Pyrenees. The Mallos were formed when eroded material washed down from the slopes of the Pyrenees and became cemented together by limestone. Over time, this mixture became compacted into a large mass of conglomerate rock. \n \nEventually, erosion wore away the softer, more porous parts of the conglomerate. The more resistant rock remained, and became the formations known as the Mallos de Riglos. Because of their relatively vertical sides, the Mallos de Riglos are a popular destination for climbers.</string>
    <string name="place_canarias">Islas Canarias</string>
    <string name="orchilla">Faro de Orchilla</string>
    <string name="description_orchilla">Punta de la Orchilla on the south-western side of El Hierro, is a significant location in terms of the Canaries, as it is one of the most westerly points in the archipelago. A meridian memorial close to the lighthouse, is a reminder that historically it was considered to be a prime meridian for early map makers, and was known as the Ferro Meridian, at the western extremity of the known world. The name comes from the Orchil lichen that grows on the rocky lava slopes in the area, inland from the point is a 238m peak called Orchilla. \n \nThe isolated locality of the Punta de la Orchilla means that it has been described as “probably Spain\'s most remote lighthouse”, reaching the site requires a 25 km trip from Sabinosa via a road that is only partly metalled, the end of the road being both unmade, and uneven. Although the site is accessible, the tower and buildings are closed.</string>
    <string name="fuencaliente">Salinas de Fuencaliente</string>
    <string name="description_fuencaliente">In the south of the island of La Palma you will discover these curious salt fields, which have been declared an Official Site of Scientific Interest owing to the fact that many migratory birds use the site to rest. One of the most visited parts of all La Palma, here the earth, air and water join forces to form the salt fields of Fuencaliente, a hugely valuable human landscape where the contrasts of the white of the salt, the blue of the sea and the black of the volcanic earth paint a picture of immense beauty. Nature’s colour palette paints the salt fields in a spectacular manner. The sea water is trapped between stone and mud which forms a labyrinth where the sun evaporates off the liquid, leaving behind the salt. This produces incredible colour effects from yellow to blue, passing through hues of pink. The small, sparkly crystals are collected by hand and formed into small pyramids, which are dried by the air. \n \nIn the Jardín de la Sal, a themed restaurant, you can learn about the production process and purchase high-quality products such as the Flor de Sal, or Salt Flower, the purest form of salt.</string>
    <string name="timanfaya">Timanfaya</string>
    <string name="description_timanfaya">Timanfaya National Park is a Spanish national park in the southwestern part of the island of Lanzarote, Canary Islands. It covers parts of the municipalities Tinajo and Yaiza. The area is 51.07 square kilometres (19.72 sq mi).[1] The parkland is entirely made up of volcanic soil. The statue "El Diablo" by César Manrique is its symbol. The greatest recorded eruptions occurred between 1730 and 1736. The volcanic activity continues as the surface temperature in the core ranges from 100 to 600 °C (212 to 1,112 °F) at the depth of 13 metres (43 ft), which is demonstrated by pouring water into the ground, resulting in a geyser of steam which is an attraction for tourists. There is only one active volcano, Timanfaya volcano after which the park is named. \n \nIn 1993, UNESCO designated a Biosphere reserve covering the whole of Lanzarote. The national park is one of the core areas of the biosphere reserve. Access to the park by the public is strictly regulated to protect the delicate flora and fauna. There are one or two footpaths, and a popular short route where one can visit by camel. There is a public car park from which one can tour the volcanic landscape by coach using a road that is otherwise closed to the public.</string>
    <string name="place_castilla_leon">Castilla y León</string>
    <string name="duraton">Hoces del Duratón</string>
    <string name="description_duraton">Hoces del Rio Duratón Natural Park is a natural park of 5,037 hectares 1,2 km West from Sepúlveda, Segovia. Its name refers to the Duratón River. "Las Hoces" refers to the series of 100m high gorges that were formed by the Duratón. Saint Fructus (San Frutos) established himself here as a hermit in the 8th century; a monastery dedicated to him also exists within the park. The park encompasses the towns of Sepúlveda, Sebúlcor and Carrascal del Río. It is home to a population of griffon vultures, along with Egyptian vultures, common kestrels, and peregrine falcons.</string>
    <string name="place_galicia">Galicia</string>
    <string name="canon_sil">Cañón del Sil</string>
    <string name="description_canon_sil">Sil Canyon is a gorge in Galicia, Spain along the Sil. it covers the last 50 km before the Sil enters the Minho. The scenery is considered to be the most spectacular in Galicia. The walls rise almost vertically up to 500 m from water level. Due to the extraordinary terrain, the local climate differs from surrounding areas and allows the growth of Mediterranean vegetation, such as olive trees. The river cliffs have been terraced to allow production of grape vines. Wine production started in this area already in Roman times. The area is called Ribeira Sacra wine region, and it is the only place in Galicia that produces more red than white wine. The gorge is classified in Natura 2000 as a site of community importance. It is a home to several rare bird species, and some mammals such as otters and bats.</string>
    <string name="place_madrid">Comunidad de Madrid</string>
    <string name="mendoza">Castillo de Mendoza</string>
    <string name="description_mendoza">The New Castle of Manzanares el Real, also known as Castle of los Mendoza, is a palace-fortress erected in the 15th century in the town of Manzanares el Real (Community of Madrid, Spain), next to the Santillana reservoir at the foot of Sierra de Guadarrama mountain range. Its construction began in 1475 on a Romanesque-Mudéjar hermitage and today is one of the best preserved castles of the Community of Madrid. It was raised on the river Manzanares, as a residential palace of the House of Mendoza, in the vicinity of an ancient fortress that was abandoned once the new castle was built. \n \nThe castle now houses a museum of Spanish castles and hosts a collection of tapestries. It was declared a Monumento Histórico-Artístico in 1931. It is owned by the Duchy of the Infantado, but its management is the responsibility of the Community of Madrid.</string>
    <string name="place_valencia">Comunidad Valenciana</string>
    <string name="paella">Paella</string>
    <string name="description_paella">Paella is a Valencian rice dish that has ancient roots but its modern form originated in the mid-19th century in the area around Albufera lagoon on the east coast of Spain adjacent to the city of Valencia. Many non-Spaniards view paella as Spain\'s national dish, but most Spaniards consider it to be a regional Valencian dish. Valencians, in turn, regard paella as one of their identifying symbols. Types of paella include, Valencian paella, vegetable paella (Spanish: paella de verduras), seafood paella (Spanish: paella de mariscos), and mixed paella (Spanish: paella mixta), among many others. Valencian paella is believed to be the original recipe and consists of white rice, green beans (bajoqueta and tavella), meat (chicken, duck and rabbit), white beans (garrofó), snails, and seasoning such as saffron and rosemary. \n \nAnother very common but seasonal ingredient is artichokes. Seafood paella replaces meat with seafood and omits beans and green vegetables. Mixed paella is a free-style combination of meat from land animals, seafood, vegetables, and sometimes beans. Most paella chefs use bomba rice due to it being less likely to overcook, but Valencians tend to use a slightly stickier (and thus more susceptible to overcooking) variety known as Senia. All types of paellas use olive oil.</string>
    <string name="cocido_madrileno">Cocido madrileño</string>
    <string name="description_cocido_madrileno">Madrid cocido is said to be eaten in three stages. First, the soup is served with the noodles (which have to be cooked in the broth for 5 minutes). Then come the chickpeas in a serving dish with the vegetables: the sautéed cabbage, the carrot and the turnip in slices (around 2 cm).Add the onion to the broth to give it flavour, but then remove it. It is also accompanied by the mix and, in a gravy boat, peeled, chopped and fried tomato. The third stage consists of the pieces of meat, pork, bacon and the marrow bones. The marrow spread on toast is delicious.</string>
    <string name="place_asturias">Asturias</string>
    <string name="fabada">Fabada asturiana</string>
    <string name="description_fabada">Fabada asturiana, often simply known as fabada, is a rich Spanish bean stew, originally from and most commonly found in the autonomous community of Principality of Asturias, but widely available throughout the whole of Spain and in Spanish restaurants worldwide. Canned fabada is sold in most supermarkets across the country. Fabada is a hot and heavy dish and for that reason is most commonly eaten during winter and at the largest meal of the day, lunch. It is usually served as a starter, but may also be the main course of the meal. \n \nIt is typically served with Asturian cider or a red wine. Fabada is made with dried large white beans (fabes de la Granja, soaked overnight before use), shoulder of pork (Lacón Gallego) or bacon (tocino), black pudding (morcilla), chorizo, and often saffron (azafrán). Some recipes also call for longaniza.</string>
    <string name="all_spain">All Spain</string>
    <string name="jamon">Jamón ibérico</string>
    <string name="description_jamon">"Iberian ham" is a type of cured ham produced in Spain and Portugal. According to Spain\'s Denominación de Origen rules on food products, jamón ibérico may be made from black Iberian pigs, or cross-bred pigs so long as they are at least 50% ibérico. The hams are labeled according to the pigs\' diet and the percentage of the pigs' Iberian ancestry, with an acorn diet and pure-bred Iberians being most desirable. Until 2007, jamón ibérico was not available in the United States.</string>
    <string name="place_andalucia">Andalucía</string>
    <string name="gazpacho">Gazpacho</string>
    <string name="description_gazpacho">Gazpacho or Andalusian gazpacho is a cold soup made of raw, blended vegetables. A classic of Spanish cuisine, it originated in the southern region of Andalusia. Gazpacho is widely eaten in Spain and Portugal, particularly during the hot summers, as it is refreshing and cool. There are other recipes called gazpacho, such as gazpacho manchego, which is very different from Andalusian gazpacho. There are also a number of dishes that are closely related to Andalusian gazpacho and often considered variants thereof, such as ajo blanco, salmorejo, pipirrana, porra antequerana (closer to a bread soup), cojondongo and Portuguese gaspacho. Gazpacho has ancient roots. There are a number of theories of its origin, including as a soup of bread, olive oil, water and garlic that arrived in Spain and Portugal with the Romans and also with the addition of vinegar. Once in Spain, it became a part of Andalusian cuisine, particularly Córdoba, Seville and Granada, using stale bread, garlic, olive oil, salt, and vinegar, similar to ajoblanco. During the 19th century, the red gazpacho evolved when tomatoes were added among the ingredients. This version was spread internationally. \n \nThere are many modern variations of gazpacho, often in different colors and omitting the tomatoes and bread in favor of avocados, cucumbers, parsley, watermelon, grapes, meat stock, seafood, and other ingredients.</string>
    <string name="tortilla">Tortilla de patata</string>
    <string name="description_tortilla">Spanish omelette is the English name for a traditional dish from Spanish cuisine called tortilla española, tortilla de patatas or tortilla de papas. It is an omelette made with eggs and potatoes, sometimes also with onion and/or chives or garlic; fried in oil and often served cold as an appetizer. It is part of the cuisine of Spain. In Spanish tortilla is the diminutive form of torta, cake; this dish is called tortilla de patatas or tortilla española to distinguish it from a plain omelette (tortilla francesa, literally "French omelette"). These dishes are unrelated to the maize or wheat tortilla of Mexico and neighbouring countries, which is a thin flatbread. In most of Latin America, where both the flatbread and potato omelette are eaten, the omelette is called tortilla española to distinguish it from the maize tortilla of the region. Because the potato is called papa in much of Latin America (instead of the term patata used in Spain), this dish can sometimes be referred to as tortilla de papas in that region as well.</string>
    <string name="pulpo">Tortilla de patata</string>
    <string name="description_pulpo">This dish is prepared by first boiling the octopus inside a copper cauldron. Before actually boiling it, the octopus\' tentacles are dipped in and out of the boiling water three times, held by its head. The objective of this operation is to curl the tips of the tentacles. The tentacles are preferred over the head, which sometimes is discarded. After the octopus has been boiled, it is trimmed with scissors, sprinkled with coarse salt and both sweet and spicy paprika (known in Galicia as pemento and pemento picante) and drizzled with olive oil. The optimal cooking point is the one in which octopus is not rubbery but not overcooked either, similarly to the al dente concept in Italian pasta cooking. This is achieved after approximately a 40 to 90 minutes boil, provided that the octopus is left to rest for a further 20 minutes inside the boiled water away from the fire. The dish is traditionally served on wooden plates and bread. Tradition dictates that drinking water should not accompany octopus, so the dish is usually accompanied by young Galician red wine. \n \nTraditionally, this diatopic use of octopus was facilitated by its inland availability as stockfish. In the last decades, frozen octopus has replaced dried octopus. Fresh octopus is not so frequently used nowadays either, as it is necessary to pound it heavily before cooking to avoid the dish becoming rubbery. This procedure can be skipped after freezing, which, unlike other seafood, does not alter the organoleptic properties of octopus. The provinces of Ourense and Lugo have a reputation for good octopus cooking. Fair style octopus is the totemic food of the patron saint festivities of Lugo (San Froilán). Some Galician cooks specialize in this dish. They are usually women, known by the name polbeiras (Galician name).After the modern decline of traditional rural fairs, many polberías (octopus restaurants, by its Galician name)[1] have sprouted across the Galician geography. Polbeiras tend to be rough and ready eateries, rather than refined restaurants.</string>
    <string name="rabo_toro">Rabo de Toro</string>
    <string name="description_rabo_toro">Oxtail (occasionally spelled ox tail or ox-tail) is the culinary name for the tail of cattle. Formerly, it referred only to the tail of a steer. An oxtail typically weighs 2 to 4 lbs. (1–1.8 kg) and is skinned and cut into short lengths for sale. Oxtail is a gelatin-rich meat, which is usually slow-cooked as a stew or braised. It is a traditional stock base for a soup. Traditional preparations involve slow cooking, so some modern recipes take a shortcut using a pressure cooker. It is a popular flavour for powder, instant and premade canned soups in the United Kingdom and Ireland. Oxtails are also one of the popular bases for Russian aspic appetizer dishes (холодец or студень), along with pig trotters or ears or cow "knees", but are the preferred ingredients among Russian Jews because they can be Kosher. \n \nVersions of oxtail soup are popular traditional dishes in South America, West Africa, China, Spain and Indonesia. </string>
    <string name="place_pais_vasco">País Vasco</string>
    <string name="merluza">Merluza en salsa verde</string>
    <string name="description_merluza">This dish is a typical one from the vasque cuisine, and its main ingredient is hake accompanied by green salse and clams. Traditionally, it is served in a clay pot with a chopped boiled egg. This recipe is very common in the daily menu of the spanish restaurants.</string>
    <string name="place_extemadura">Extremadura</string>
    <string name="migas">Migas</string>
    <string name="description_migas">Migas is the name used for an ancient dish in Spanish and Portuguese cuisines. Migas is a traditional dish in Spanish cuisine. Originally a breakfast dish that made use of leftover bread or tortas, today migas is a fashionable first course served for lunch and dinner in restaurants in Spain. The ingredients of migas vary across the provinces of Spain. In Extremadura, this dish includes day-old bread soaked in water, garlic, paprika, and olive oil, and contains spinach or alfalfa, often served with pan-fried pork ribs. In Teruel, Aragon, migas include chorizo and bacon, and is often served with grapes. \n \nIn La Mancha, migas manchegas is a more elaborate preparation using basically the same ingredients as Aragonese migas. In Almería and Murcia, in southeastern Spain, migas is similar to North African couscous, using flour and water, but no bread. Preparations commonly include a variety of ingredients, including fish. In Almería it is traditional to cook them when it rains. </string>
    <string name="place_navarra">Navarra</string>
    <string name="zurra">Zurra/Pandorga</string>
    <string name="fallas">Fallas</string>
    <string name="carnaval">Carnaval</string>
    <string name="isidro">San Isidro</string>
    <string name="feria">Feria de Abril</string>
    <string name="tomatina">La Tomatina</string>
    <string name="hogueras">Hogueras de San Juan</string>
    <string name="sella">Descenso del Sella</string>
    <string name="fermines">Los Sanfermines</string>
    <string name="description_zurra">La Zurra is a celebration where thousands of people through lemonade to each other. Along with it, la Pangorga is also celebrated. Although we do not know the origins of these two festivities, we sure know we have been celebrating it for centuries. A special act is held in the Santa María del Prado\'s Cathedral, where there is an offering of flowers, fruits and field products. During la Pandorga, a figure of Pandorgo is chosen among the citizens of Ciudad Real, to represent them during the acts that take place in the city.</string>
    <string name="description_fallas">The Falles is a traditional celebration held in commemoration of Saint Joseph in the city of Valencia, Spain. The term Falles refers to both the celebration and the monuments burnt during the celebration. A number of towns in the Valencian Community have similar celebrations inspired by the original Falles de València celebration. The Falles festival was added to UNESCO\'s intangible cultural heritage of humanity list on 30 November 2016. Each neighbourhood of the city has an organised group of people, the Casal faller, that works all year long holding fundraising parties and dinners, usually featuring the noted dish, paella, a specialty of the region. Each casal faller produces a construction known as a falla which is eventually burnt. A casal faller is also known as a comissió fallera and currently there are approximately 400 registered in Valencia. \n \nThe five days and nights of Falles might be described as a continuous street party. There are a multitude of processions: historical, religious, and comedic. Crowds in the restaurants spill out into the streets. Explosions can be heard all day long and sporadically through the night. Everyone from small children to elderly people can be seen throwing fireworks and noisemakers in the streets, which are littered with pyrotechnical debris. The timing of the events is fixed, and they fall on the same date every year, though there has been discussion about holding some events on the weekend preceding the Falles, to take greater advantage of the tourist potential of the festival or changing the end date in years where it is due to occur in midweek.</string>
    <string name="description_carnaval">Los Carnavales de Cádiz is one of the best-known carnivals in Spain. Its main characteristic is humor. Through sarcasm, mockery and irony, the main groups and the people of the street "purge" the most pressing problems of today. The whole city participates in the carnival for more than two weeks each year, and the presence of this fiesta is almost constant in the city because of the recitals and contests held throughout the year. The main characteristics of the carnival in Cádiz are the acerbic criticisms, the droll plays on words, stinging sarcasm, and the irreverence of parody. While some carnivals elsewhere in the world stress the spectacular, the glamorous, or the scandalous in costumes, Cádiz distinguishes itself with how clever and imaginative its carnival attire is. \n \nIt is traditional to paint the face as a humble substitute for a mask. On Saturday, everyone wears a costume, which, many times, is related to the most polemical aspects of the news. However, the Carnival of Cádiz is most famous for the satirical groups of performers called chirigotas. Their music and their lyrics are in the center of the carnival. Carnival of Cádiz is a sociological phenomenon of special singularity. Its historical evolution, from its most remote origins until today, has endowed it with a marked rebellious character. In addition, the development of their groups (mainly their choirs, chirigotas, comparsas and quartets) differentiates them from other carnivals in the world and also identifies them as a communicational phenomenon. It is a vehicle that generates information, opinion and entertainment, but also in its subversive nature, in its condition of counter-power.</string>
    <string name="description_isidro">One of the most celebrated holidays of Madrid is held on May 15, the Feast Day of San Isidro who is the city\'s patron saint as well as the patron saint of farmers. The traditional festival and feast are held in an open-air area known as the Pradera del Santo. In the afternoon, the image of San Isidro and his wife, Santa Maria de la Cabeza, are paraded through the streets, from Calle del Sacramento to the Plaza de la Villa, via Calle del Cordon. The feast in honor of San Isidro is declared of National Tourist Interest in Andalusia and is one of the most important celebrations in province of Malaga. \n \nThe fiesta is very popular in region of Alameda because San Isidro is a patron of the town. Celebrations honoring both saints are also held elsewhere on the islands. For years, the Alicantine locality of Castalla has been celebrating the Fair of San Isidro, where numerous companies display their products in a playful and festive atmosphere. A medieval swap meet and mechanical attractions are especially popular.</string>
    <string name="description_feria">The Seville Fair (officially and in Spanish: Feria de abril de Sevilla, "Seville April Fair") is held in Andalusian capital of Seville, Spain. The fair generally begins two weeks after the Semana Santa, or Easter Holy Week. The fair officially begins at midnight on Monday, and runs six days, ending on the following Sunday. During past fairs, however, many activities have begun on the Saturday prior to the official opening. Each day the fiesta begins with the parade of carriages and riders, at midday, carrying Seville\'s leading citizens which make their way to the bullring, La Real Maestranza, where the bullfighters and breeders meet. For the duration of the fair, the fairgrounds and a vast area on the far bank of the Guadalquivir River are totally covered in rows of casetas (individual decorated marquee tents which are temporarily built on the fairground). \n \nThese casetas usually belong to prominent families of Seville, groups of friends, clubs, trade associations and political parties. From around nine at night until six or seven the following morning, at first in the streets and later only within each caseta, there are crowds partying and dancing sevillanas, drinking Sherry, manzanilla or rebujito, and eating tapas. This fair also has an amusement park that comes with it and has lots of games to play along with roller coasters to ride.</string>
    <string name="description_tomatina">La Tomatina is a festival that is held in the Valencian town of Buñol, a town located in the East of Spain 30 kilometres from the Mediterranean, in which participants throw tomatoes and get involved in this tomato fight purely for entertainment purposes. Since 1945 it has been held on the last Wednesday of August, during the week of festivities of Buñol. It started the last Wednesday of August in 1945 when some young people spent the time in the town square to attend the Giants and Big-Heads figures parade. The young boys decided to have a place among the retinue of a parade with musician, Giants and Big-Heads figures. The energy of these young people made that one participant fall off. The participant flew into a fit of rage, started to hit everything in his path. There was a market stall of vegetable that fell victim of the furious crowd: people started to pelt each other with tomatoes until the local forces ended that fruit battle. The following year, the young people picked a quarrel by their own decision and brought the tomatoes from home. \n \nAlthough the police broke up the early tradition in the following years, the young boys had made history without being conscious about it. La Tomatina was banned in the early 50s, which was not a problem for the participants who were even arrested. But the people spoke and the festivity was again allowed with more participants and more frenetic feelings. The festivity was again cancelled till 1957 when, as a sign of protest, the tomato burial was held. It was a demonstration in which the residents carried a coffin with a huge tomato inside. The parade was accompanied by a music band which played funeral marches and it was totally successful. La Tomatina Festival was finally allowed and became an official festivity. As a result of the report of Javier Basilio, broadcast in the Spanish television program called Informe Semanal, the festivity started to be known in the rest of Spain. Since then, the number of participants increased year after year as well as the excitement about La Tomatina Festival. In 2002, La Tomatina of Buñol was declared Festivity of International Tourist Interest by the Secretary Department of Tourism due to its success.</string>
    <string name="description_hogueras">The traditional midsummer party in Spain is the celebration in honour of San Juan and takes place on the evening of June 23. This midsummer tradition is especially strong in north-western areas of Spain, especially in Galicia, where San Xoán festivals take place all over the region; bonfires are lit and a set of firework displays usually takes place. On the Mediterranean coast, especially in Catalonia and Valencia, special foods, such as Coca de Sant Juan, are also served on this occasion. There is also a large festival in Ciutadella, Menorca, along with many other different cities and towns all across Spain having their own unique traditions associated with the festival. Bonfires are also used in the Basque Country to celebrate San Juan Eguna (the feast of St. John the Baptist), which marks the Basque Summer Solstice. \n \nIn some towns the celebration is supplemented with more festivities and dances. In Castilla y León it is highlighted the Firewalking Festival of San Pedro Manrique (Soria), where barefoot men cross the live coals of a prepared bonfire.</string>
    <string name="description_sella">The International descent of the River Sella is an annual canoeing event that takes place iin Asturias around the first weekend in August. It\'s one of the largest canoeing races of its kind in the world attracting participants all over the globe to take part. The race starts in the town of Arriondas which is nestled at the foot hills of the Picos de Europa and makes it way along a 20km stretch of the river Sella finishing at the seaside resort of Ribadesella. The race is the center point of a four day festival that offers concerts and plenty of activities to do which attracts many visitors to the area, most of whom are just there to party and party they do! Like at most festivals in Asturias, the revelers tend to be easy going and out to have a good time. \n \nDespite the sheer number of people in attendance, the festival is good for families and all age groups. The International descent of the River Sella started back ini 1929 when Dionisio dela Huerta made the recreational trip down the river with a few friends. Since then, the race has grown in popularity and its now recognized by UNESCO as a world heritage tourism event. The organizers have worked hard to develop the develop the event and have made many changes including opening the race to disabled participants.</string>
    <string name="description_fermines">The festival of San Fermín is a week-long, historically rooted celebration held annually in the city of Pamplona, Navarre, Spain. The celebrations start at noon on the sixth of July, when the party starts with the setting off the pyrotechnic chupinazo,[a] and continue until midnight, on the fourteenth of July, with the singing of the Pobre de Mí. While its most famous event is the encierro, or the running of the bulls, at 8:00 AM from July 7 to 14, the festival involves many other traditional and folkloric events. \n \nIt is known locally as Sanfermines and is held in honor of Saint Fermin, the co-patron of Navarre. Its events were central to the plot of The Sun Also Rises, by Ernest Hemingway, which brought it to the general attention of English-speaking people. It has become probably the most internationally renowned fiesta in Spain. Over 1,000,000 people come to participate in this festival.</string>
    <string name="place_baleares">Islas Baleares</string>
    <string name="place_rioja">La Rioja</string>
    <string name="berasategui">Martín Berasategui</string>
    <string name="description_berasategui">5 minutes away from San Sebastián and sourrounded by the beauty of the vasque countryside, we can find this pinned restaurant owned by Martín Berasategui. Its imaginative, innovative, fresh and rooted with the environment cooking, along with an excellent wine cellar creates the perfect place to enjoy a delicious and excellent meal.</string>
    <string name="roca">El Celler de Can Roca</string>
    <string name="description_roca">The Roca brothers\' passion for cooking was initially kindled in Can Roca, the establishment their parents manage in Taialà, a neighbourhood lying on the outskirts of Gerona. /n /nIt is where they grew up, amid the hubbub of dishes, pots and pans and clients. The bar was their living room, their playground, where they did their homework, watched television, etc. whence the aroma of the stews generously, simply and honestly prepared by their mother, wafted in.</string>
    <string name="azurmendi">Azurmendi</string>
    <string name="description_azurmendi">In 2015 it was declared the best restaurant in Europe, according to Steve Plotnicki, creator of the Opinionated About Dining guide, one of the most pretigious restaurants calification index of the world. Azurmendi also has three Michelin stars, making lead the list of the 100 best restaurants in Europe.</string>
    <string name="calo">Es Caló Restaurant</string>
    <string name="description_calo">The perfect marinaje between landscape and gastronomy. Welcome to the world of flavors created from the illusion of a group of hospitality professionals in Es Calo. If you look outside, discover a magical setting where the sea and the rocks at La Mola draw a small cove, called Es Calo. This unique landscape requires us to offer you a gastronomic symphony worthy of him and what you expect from us.</string>
    <string name="disfrutar">Disfrutar</string>
    <string name="description_disfrutar">Located in the Eixample, just in front of the Ninot Market, the premises are also surprising due to their design. Respect for the history and legacy of the Mediterranean are the inspiration and ceramic is the common theme marking the interior. The entrance area is inspired by Barcelona, by the wrought iron of the Ninot Market and the colours of Mironian ceramics. The central corridor, made from ceramic with the colours and textures of clay, goes through the kitchen which is completely visible to clients and leads to the main dining room. This is inspired by small fishing villages and stands out as a bright, white space, that transports one outside the city and connects with the terrace; a nod to share. In short, surprisingly Mediterranean premises, with an intimate and welcoming manner, and creative cuisine designed to “Disfrutar”.</string>
    <string name="bodega">La Vieja Bodega</string>
    <string name="description_bodega">The desire of this restaurant is to offer the customer the finest produce, treated with the utmost care, attention and professionalism. Their menu offers a wide variety of dishes, with the chance to try classics from the region – some of them fully retooled – alongside their chef\'s personal creations. Come along and try them out!</string>
    <string name="uma">UMA</string>
    <string name="description_uma">If you are visiting Barcelona, this is a must. The cooking represents the fusion of Iker Erauzkin personality. There are only five tables available, sourrounded by curious decoration. There is an elaborated menu offered each day based on the product that the cooks can find in the market. If you want to enjoy two and a half hours in this place, which is how long it takes to savour the menu, you must book as soon as possible, since there is a waiting list.</string>
    <string name="dstage">Dstage</string>
    <string name="description_dstage">Diego Guerrero has created a unique concept, and still has no idea how far it can be taken. Something never done before. This is what makes Diego Guerrero an extraordinary chef. He was capable of exploring his innermost self and turning what he discovered into reality.</string>
    <string name="diverxo">Diverxo</string>
    <string name="description_diverxo">New unexplored ways of understanding the gastronomic experience. Unique cuisine marked by intense sensations and raw creativity.</string>
    <string name="recomiendo">ReComiendo</string>
    <string name="description_recomiendo">ReComiendo is a welcoming, simple and familiar place, with a sober and elegant decoration which gives the importance to the fact of eating. This restaurants pretends to create a feeling, to find excellence in what they do, to get the "is never enough" and "I want more".</string>
</resources>
